我们目前有三个
we currently have three
服务器进程
server processes
应该连续运行并且不会错过任何一个节拍
that should run continuously and never miss a beat
但事情并不总是按计划进行
but things don't always go according to plan
是的，一个进程可能会崩溃
yeah a process can crash
当它发生时，我们需要采取行动
and when it does we need to take action
所以我们的应用程序不会错过任何一个节拍
so our application doesn't miss a beat
现在为这种容错设计
now designing for this sort of fault tolerance
听起来很艰巨
sounds like a tall order
但它已融入 erlangvm 和 otp 库
but it's baked into the erlangvm and the otp libraries
这是我们的三个服务器进程 http server
here are our three server processes http server
质押服务器和传感器服务器
pledge server and sensor server
我们如何才能使这些流程能够适应故障
how can we make these processes resilient to failures
好吧，我们想把一些东西到位
well we want to put in place something
这将启动每个过程
that will start each process
持续监控该过程
continuously monitor that process
然后如果它检测到进程崩溃了
and then if it detects that the process crashed
在它的位置开始一个新的过程
start a new process in its place
那么我们将如何做到这一点
so how are we going to do that
在质押服务器和传感器服务器的情况下
well in the case of pledge server and sensor server
这些进程是 gen server 进程
these processes are gen server processes
并且 otp 包括主管行为
and otp includes a supervisor behavior
我们将在下一个模块中使用
that we'll use in the next module to start
根据需要监控和启动新流程
monitor and start new processes as necessary
但 tp 服务器进程不是 gen 服务器进程
but the htp server process isn't a gen server process
这是一个常规的长生不老药过程
it's a regular elixir process that
不遵循 otp 约定
doesn't follow the otp conventions
并作为
and as
这样我们就不能使用内置的主管行为
such we can't use the built in supervisor behavior
相反，我们将编写一个简单的生成服务器进程，因为
instead we'll write a simple gen server process because
正如我们将看到的，我们希望它很长
as we'll see we want it to be a long
处理消息和存储状态的运行进程
running process that handles messages and store state
我们将命名一个kickstarter
and we'll name a kickstarter
考虑启动摩托车而不是
think of kickstarting a motorcycle instead of the
热门融资平台
popular funding platform
此过程将启动 http 服务器
this process will start the http server
处理然后使用称为链接的东西
process and then use something called a link
检测该进程何时崩溃
to detect when that process crashes
所以它可以开始一个新的进程
so it can start a new process
了解链接过程是
and learning about linking processes is fundamental to
了解 otp 主管行为的工作原理
understanding how the otp supervisor behavior works
在引擎盖下
under the hood
好的，让我们创建 kickstarter 模块
all right so let's create the kickstarter module
kickstarter dx
这可能是服务启动器
this could be serve kickstarter
然后我们希望这是一个生成服务器
and then we want this to be a gen server
所以我们要说使用 gen server
so we're going to say use gen server
然后就像我们的其他一代服务器一样
and then just like our other gen servers
我们将编写一个启动包装函数
we'll write a start wrapper function
我们先说 ioputas
and we'll just start off by saying ioputas
启动kickstarter
starting the kickstarter
然后它需要调用 gen server start
and then it needs to call gen server start
实际启动 gen 服务器进程
to actually start up the gen server process
然后这个模块
and then this module
kickstarter 将成为回调模块
kickstarter is going to be the callback module
所以我们将它设置为回调模块
so we'll set that as the callback module
然后我们没有任何状态
and then we don't have any state
所以我们只使用原子 ok 作为状态
so we'll just use the atom ok for the state
然后我们也想注册这个进程
and then we also want to register this process
在一个名字下，名字是
under a name and the name is
实际上只是模块的名称
actually just going to be the name of the module
所以我们将再次使用它
so we'll use this again
所以这个过程的名字就是
so the name of the process is just going to be
调查启动器
survey kickstarter
kickstarter 进程何时开始
when the kickstarter process starts
我们还想启动一个http服务器进程
we also want to start an http server process
我们将其称为 Web 服务器进程
we'll refer to this as the web server process
从现在开始，我们将在 nit 回调函数中执行此操作
from now on we'll do that in the nit callback function
并且因为我们在 genserver start 中使用了 adam ok
and because we use the adam ok in genserver start
好吧，它也需要在那里好，我们
well it needs to take ok right there too and we
知道
know
这将由 genserver 自动调用
this is going to be automatically invoked by genserver
开始，因为我们在这里通过
start and because we pass ok right here
好
well
这就是为什么我们在这里需要 ok 以便模式匹配
that's why we need ok here so that a pattern matches
它运行这个功能
and it runs this function
然后我们就打印出来
then we'll just print out
启动hdp服务器
starting the hdp server
然后启动它，我们将使用 spawn
and then to start it up we're going to use spawn
服务 hdp 服务器
serve hdp server
功能是开始
the function is start
然后我们想将端口 4000 传递给它
and then we want to pass it the port 4000
就像我们做过很多次一样
just like we've done many times
然后我们将捕获服务器 pid
and then we'll capture the server pid
另一方面
on the other side
哎呀，这实际上需要是 4000 而不是 400
oops this actually needs to be 4000 instead of 400
好吧，让我们
all right and let's
还要在别名下注册 Web 服务器进程
also register the web server process under an alia
所以很容易证明崩溃它
so it's easy to demonstrate crashing it
我们只会说进程注册
we'll just say process register
服务器 pid
the server pid
我们将在 score server 下将其命名为 http
and we'll just name it http under score server
那么我们需要确保返回一个元组
then we need to make sure to return a tuple
与国家
with the state
作为服务器 pid
being the server pid
所以会没事的
so it'll be okay
然后状态就是
and then the state is just
该服务器引脚
that server pin
所以让我们把它拿走，在我里面快速旋转一下
so let's take this away and give it a quick whirl in I
耶克斯
yex
所以要启动kickstarter，我们使用调查kickstarter
so to start the kickstarter we use survey kickstarter
dot start 那是我们的包装函数
dot start that's our wrapper function
这将返回两次拉动 ok
and this is going to return a two pull with ok
还有坑我叫它kick pid
and the pit I'm going to call it the kick pid
记住
remember
start 正在调用 gen server start 和 gen server start
start is calling gen server start and gen server start
总是返回一个元组
always returns a tuple
好的，然后是一些坑
ok and then some pit
所以我们在左侧进行模式匹配
so we're pattern matching that on the left hand side
很酷，我们看到这两个 kickstarter 过程
cool we see that both the kickstarter process
并且网络服务器进程开始了
and the web server process got started
现在如果 Web 服务器进程崩溃会发生什么
now what happens if the web server process crashes
由于某些原因
for some reason
我们可以将其设置为崩溃
we could set it up to crash by
在代码中引发异常
raising an exception in the code
而不是更改代码
but rather than changing the code
我们可以通过发送一个
we can cause the process to crash by sending it an
退出信号
exit signal
所以首先我们需要找到那个网络服务器进程
so first we need to find that web server process
我们想掌握 pid
we want to get a hold of the pid
因为我们注册了一个别名，所以我们可以使用 process
because we registered an alias we can use process
有一个功能在哪里
there's a where is function
然后我们把它的名字传给它
and then we pass it the name
过程的
of the process
我们注册了
we registered
http服务器
http server
好了，我们已经将 pid 存储在服务器 pid 中
there we go we've got the pids stored in server pid
然后让它崩溃，我们可以使用 process 模块
and then to crash it we can use the process module
再次有一个名为 exit 的函数
again there's a function called exit
我们给它服务器 pid
we give it the server pid
然后我们给它理由
and then we give it the reason
它应该退出
that it should exit
我只是要使用 atom caboom
and I'm just going to use the atom caboom
好吧，现在让我们看看它是否还活着
all right now let's see if that's still alive
不，网络服务器不再存在
nope the web server isn't alive anymore
但是kickstarter流程呢
but what about the kickstarter process
如果我们在这里传入 kickpid
if we pass in kickpid here
好吧，它返回true
well it returns true
所以kickstarter进程仍然存在
so the kickstarter process is still alive
反之亦然
the reverse is also true
如果我们要让 kickstarter 进程崩溃
if we were to crash the kickstarter process
它不会影响 Web 服务器进程
it wouldn't affect the web server process
谁默认两个进程是独立运行的
who by default both processes run in isolation
但我们需要一种方法让 kickstarter 检测到
but we need a way for kickstarter to detect
当 Web 服务器进程崩溃时
when the web server process crashes
好的，那么一个进程将如何监视另一个进程
okay so how is one process going to monitor the other
好吧，我们可以将它们联系在一起
well we can link them together
我们在这里的 nit 函数中
we're in the nit function here
我们已经产生了 hdp 服务器进程
and we've spawned the hdp server process
然后我们可以说流程链接
then right after that we can say process link
服务器坑
server pit
因为我们正在调用过程链接
and because we're calling process link
从 kickstarter 流程中
from within the kickstarter process
因为它在这里被初始化
because it's getting initialized here
然后该kickstarter流程现在已链接
then that kickstarter process is now linked
到 web 服务器进程
to the web server process
就是服务器pid对应的进程
that's the process corresponding to server pid
让我们在新的 iex 会话中给这个另一个世界
let's give this another world in a new iex session
这样我们就不用担心清理
that way we don't have to worry about cleaning up
注册进程
registered processes
所以首先我们需要启动kickstarter进程
so first we need to fire up the kickstarter process
然后我们需要找到我们的http服务器进程
then we need to find our http server process
当我们启动kickstarter时
and when we started up the kickstarter
调用了 nit 函数
the nit function was called
所以现在这两个过程应该联系起来
so now these two processes should be linked
我们可以通过使用 process 模块找到
we can find out by using the process module
info 函数会给它 kickpid
the info function will give it the kickpid
然后我们会问它你的链接是什么
and then we'll ask it what are your links
好吧，它与流程一六十六有关
well it's linked to process one sixty six
这是我们的hdp服务器进程
which is our hdp server process
那么反过来呢
so what about the reverse
服务器进程链接到什么
what is the server process link to
好吧，它与 pid 1 65 相关联
well it's linked to pid one sixty five
这是我们的启动程序
which is our kickstarter process
我们看到它是什么时候开始的
we see when it got started up there
这是它的 pid 1 65
that's the pid of it one sixty five
现在您还看到它链接到一个端口
now you also see that it's linked to a port
港口只是一种方式
a port is just a way
让 Elixir 与外部程序通信
for elixir to communicate with external programs
与流程的链接没有任何关系
doesn't have anything to do with linking of processes
这里的关键是这两个处理器是链接的
here the key thing is these two processors are linked
通过定向
by directionally
所以 kickstarter pid 引用 hdp 服务器 pid
so the kickstarter pid references the hdp server pid
和 hdp 服务器 pid
and the hdp server pid
与 kickstarter 流程相关联
is linked to the kickstarter process
所以现在让我们让 Web 服务器进程崩溃
so now let's crash the web server process
就像我们以前一样
just like we did before
通过向它发送退出信号 caboom
by sending it the exit signal caboom
所以它死了但是我们的kickstarter过程会发生什么
so it dies but what happens to our kickstarter process
嗯，这次也崩溃了
ah well this time it also crashed
所以这就是幕后发生的事情
so here's what happened behind the scenes
我们向 hdp 服务器进程发送了退出信号
we sent an exit signal to the hdp server process
导致它终止
that caused it to terminate
然后通知了
it then notified the
通过发送相同的链接来链接kickstarter流程
linked kickstarter process by sending it the same
退出信号和
exit signal and
因为退出信号表示进程退出
because the exit signal indicates the process exited
异常
abnormally
然后链接的kickstarter进程也崩溃了
then the linked kickstarter process crashed as well
因此，当我们将两个进程联系起来时，它们的命运是紧密相连的
so when we link two processes their fates are tied
一起当一个崩溃另一个崩溃
together when one crashes the other one crashes
但这并不是我们想要的
but that's not exactly what we want
我们不希望 kickstarter 进程崩溃
we don't want the kickstarter process to crash
如果 Web 服务器进程崩溃
if the web server process crashes
kickstarter 需要继续运行
the kickstarter needs to continue running
所以它可以重新启动网络服务器
so it can restart the web server
这实际上意味着启动一个新的 Web 服务器进程
which really means starting a new web server process
没有办法真正重启一个死进程
there's no way to actually restart a dead process
我们只想开始一个新的进程
we just want to start a new process
要做到这一点
to do that
kickstarter 进程需要捕获退出信号
the kickstarter process needs to trap exit signals
我们将在 nit 函数的第一步中进行
and we'll do it in the first step of the nit function
我们使用过程
we use process
有一个函数叫做 flag
there's a function called flag
标志是陷阱出口
the flag is trap exit
然后我们只想传入 true
and then we just want to pass in true
现在得到的任何退出信号
now any exit signals that get
从链接的 Web 服务器进程传播不会
propagated from the linked web server process won't
导致 kickstarter 进程崩溃
cause the kickstarter process to crash
所以让我们看看我们的陷阱在新的 iex 会话中捕获了什么
so let's see what our trap catches in a new iex session
启动 kickstarter 进程
fire up the kickstarter process
找到网络服务器进程
find the web server process
然后我们需要 caboom 网络服务器进程
then we need to caboom the web server process
哦，这次我们收到一条错误消息
ooh this time we get an error message
现在我们将在一分钟内回到那个
now we'll come back to that in a minute
但是我们的kickstarter过程发生了什么
but what happened to our kickstarter process
好吧，它还活着
well it's still alive
所以即使这两个过程是联系在一起的
so even though both processes are linked
kickstarter 进程没有崩溃
the kickstarter process didn't crash
这正是我们想要的
that's exactly what we wanted
现在回到错误消息，它是纯金
now back to the error message and it's pure gold
据说kickstarter进程收到了
it's saying that the kickstarter process received an
意外消息
unexpected message
这是消息
and here's the message
所以kickstarter捕获了退出信号
so kickstarter trapped the exit signal
网络服务器崩溃时发送的
sent by the web server when it crashed
并将退出信号转换为消息
and converted the exit signal to a message
我们看到原子退出
we see the atom exit
然后这里的第二个元素是pid
and then the second element here is the pid
这是导致崩溃的进程一六十六
this is the process that crashed one sixty six
这是我们的网络服务器进程
which is our web server process
然后是第三个元素
and then the third element
只是它崩溃的原因
is just the reason it crashed
好吧，这就是原子驾驶舱
well it's that atom caboom
因为这只是一个简单的信息
and because this is just a plain message
这不是电话或演员表
it's not a call or a cast
然后 gen server 期望它被处理
then gen server expects it to be handled
在句柄信息回调中
in a handle info callback
这就是为什么我们在
which is why we see received unexpected message in
它试图调用句柄信息的句柄信息
handle info it's trying to invoke handle info
带有与此模式匹配的消息
with a message that matches this pattern
所以在我们的 kickstarter 模块中，我们只需要一个句柄信息
so in our kickstarter module we just need a handle info
与此消息匹配的回调
callback that matches this message
并重新启动 Web 服务器
and restarts the web server
处理信息
handle info
接着
and then
我复制了 ix 中的消息，所以我可以
I copied the message that was in ix so I can just
粘贴到这里
paste it in right here
然后我就改变它
and then I'll just change it
所以这将是
so this is going to be
终止进程的pid
the pid of the terminated process
我们不需要那个
we don't need that
所以我要使用下划线
so I'm going to use an underscore
所以我们不会收到警告
so we don't get a warning
这将是原因
and this is going to be the reason
然后因为这个句柄信息
and then because of this handle info
第二个参数永远是状态
the second argument is always going to be the state
我们也不会使用它
and we're not going to use it either
所以我将在那里使用下划线状态
so I'm going to use underscore state there
然后我们将从打印开始
and then we'll start by just printing off
http 服务器已退出
http server exited
然后在 printheses 中将检查原因
and then in printheses will just inspect the reason
你可能想永久记录这个空气
you likely want to permanently log this air
所以你有取证来帮助诊断问题
so you have forensics to help diagnose the problem
我们现在只打印出来
we're just going to print it out for now
所以不管退出原因
so regardless of the exit reason
我们要启动一个新的 hdp 服务器进程
we want to start a new hdp server process
所以我们只需从针织品中复制这些线条
so we'll just copy these lines from a knit
现在我们稍后会清理它
right now we'll clean this up a little bit later
我们就下来这里，我会把它们粘贴进去
we'll just come down here and I'll just paste those in
然后我们只需要确保返回
and then we just need to make sure to return
预期的元组
the expected tuple
由于这是句柄信息，因此需要
and since this is handle info it needs to be
无回复
no reply
然后是即将成为的状态
and then the state which is just going to be the
新服务器坑
new server pit
因为记得
because remember
我们在那里启动了一个新的 hdb 服务器进程
we started a new hdb server process right there
将其分配给服务器 pid
assigned it to server pid
所以新的状态将是那个服务器坑
so the new state is going to be that server pit
我们将在一个新的
we'll try this in a new
iex 会议，我们应该免费回家
iex session and we should be home free
启动 kickstarter
start up the kickstarter
找到我们的 hdp 服务器
find our hdp server
驾驶它和完美
caboom it and perfect
我们看到我们启动了一个新的 Web 服务器进程
we see that we started a new web server process
现在如果我们去找那个新的网络服务器进程
and now if we go find that new web server process
然后我们再次驾驶它
and we caboom it again
好吧实际上不再
well actually not again
这完全是一个不同的过程
this is a different process entirely
好吧，我们看到我们每次都会得到一个新的 pid
well we see we're getting a new pid every time
这是 pid 1 七十三
this is pid one seventy three
在它之前一次 70 和在那之前
before it once once 70 and before that
让我们看看是一六十六
let's see it was one sixty six
这正是我们想要的
that's just what we want
所以每次我们的网络服务器死掉
so every time our web server dies
kickstarter 启动一个新进程
kickstarter starts a new process
现在，如果我们回顾一下我们的代码，我们有四个
now if we look back at our code we have four
此处重复的行
lines duplicated here
这是一个理想
which is an ideal
所以让我们将它们重构为一个启动服务器函数
so let's refactor these into a start server function
我将这些复制出来然后在下面
I'll just copy these out and then down below
在这里我们将定义这个新函数
here we'll define that new function
启动服务器，我将它们粘贴到
start server and I'll just paste those in
然后我们只需要记住返回
and then we just need to remember to return
服务器 pid 作为最后一行
the server pid as the last line there
如果您愿意，您可以将其设为私有功能
and you could make this a private function if you want
只用defp
just use defp
然后我们只需要在这里使用那个函数
and then we just need to use that function up here
所以在针织中我们可以去掉这一切
so in a knit we can remove all this
只需调用启动服务器
and just call start server
我会用我们可以做的同样的方式复制它
I'll copy that in the same way we can do that right
这里
here
实际上没有人我们也可以删除这个pudex
no one actually we can remove this pudex too
所以现在这两个功能很好很整洁
so now these two functions are nice and tidy
现在你注意到了
now you notice
下面我们叫 spawn
down here we're calling spawn
然后我们立即转身打电话
and then we're turning around immediately and calling
现在链接
link now
你经常需要一个 spawner 进程和
you often want a spawner process and
将其链接到调用进程
link it to the calling process
所以有一个捷径
so there's a shortcut for this
而不是调用 spawn
rather than calling spawn
然后链接为两个单独的步骤
and then link as two separate steps
您可以改为调用 spawn 链接函数
you can instead call the spawn link function
所以你只说spawn
so you just say spawn
像这样的链接，然后你可以摆脱那条线
link like that and then you can get rid of that line
这具有相同的效果
this has the same effect
但它更方便，而且
but it's more convenient and
也更健壮
also more robust
因为生成和链接发生在一个原子操作中
as the spawn and link happen in one atomic operation
避免任何潜在的竞争条件
to avoid any potential race conditions
现在可以进行快速的健全性检查
okay now for a quick sanity check
我们开始我们的kickstarter
we start our kickstarter
获取我们的 http 服务器
get our http server
最后一次崩溃
crash at one last time
哦，看起来它重新启动了
oh and it looks like it gets restarted
所以我们的重构并没有破坏任何东西
so our refactoring didn't break anything
所以现在如果我们的网络服务器进程崩溃了
so now if our web server process crashes
我们会自动给它一脚
we automatically give it a kick
所以希望我们不会错过对我们网站的任何请求
so hopefully we don't miss any requests to our site
接下来
next up
我们将为我们的承诺和传感器服务器做同样的事情
we'll do the same for our pledge and sensor servers